BORYANA ILIEVA

Mohrenstr. 58 10117 Berlin German Institute for Economic Research bilieva@diw.de $+49\ 30\ 89789\ 261$

Spandauer Str. 1 10117 Berlin Humbold University Berlin boryana.ilieva@hu-berlin.de

PERSONAL PROFILE AND RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a PhD candidate at the Humboldt University in Berlin, Germany. Additionally, I am affiliated to the German Institute for Economics Research, DIW Berlin. My research focus is on labor and behavioral economics. I am further interested in development and experimental economics. As a researcher, I have worked on microeconomic modelling, survey design, and empirical analysis of administrative and survey data based on both reduced form methods as well as dynamic structural models. I further have valuable international and private sector experience. An open minded team player, excited by human psychology, technology, and innovation.

CURRENT EMPLOYMENT

Humboldt University Berlin

PhD Candidate and Research Associate

Supervision and reference: Georg Weizsäcker

Microeconomic Theory and Applications Department &

Collaborative Research Center "Rationality and Competition"

German Institute for Economic Research, DIW Berlin

Research Associate and Teaching Fellow

Supervision and reference: Peter Haan phaan@diw.de

Public Economics Department

EDUCATION

Humboldt University Berlin

Master of Science in Economics and Management

Streams: Microeconomics, Econometrics, Business Analytics

International exchange scholarship:

University Sankt Gallen, Switzerland

University of Mannheim

Bachelor of Science in Economics

ERASMUS Scholarship: University Carlos III, Spain

Ruprecht-Karls University Heidelberg

'Physikum' in Medical Science

1st German Language School "Prof. Konstantin Galabov", Sofia, Bulgaria

Secondary Education

Double Degree: German & Bulgarian

October 2014 - June 2017

October 2017 - Present

October 2017 - Present

grad. expected August 2022

weizsaecker@hu-berlin.de

Overall GPA: 1.4/5

September 2015 - January 2016

2011 - 2014

Overall GPA: 1.7/5

September 2013 - January 2014

2009 - 2011

Exam Grade: 1.5/1

2004 - 2009

ACADEMIC WORK

- "Climbing the Career Ladder: Gender differences in promotions and part-time work"
- "Biased Wage Expectations and Female Labor Supply" with Maximilian Blesch, Philipp Eisenhauer, Peter Haan, Annekatrin Schrenker, and Georg Weizsäcker
- "Quantile Selection Analysis of Wages" with Peter Haan and Christoph Breunig
- "What to expect when COVID-19 lockdown ends? Individual expectations about the labor market and re-openings in the Uited States" with Katharina Baum
- "Women, Fertility, and Informality" with Marianne Bernatzky Koehli and Lucas Finamor
- "Gender and Higher Education Decision in France" with Camille Ramigereau

PRESENTATIONS, WORKSHOPS & GRANTS

1. Presentations

"CRC Retreat and Young Economist Workshop" in Tutzing, Germany

September 2019

"Joint IZA-IFS workshop", London, UK

November 2019

"Workshop on Subjective Expectations", Virtual, Laval University Canada December 2020

ASSA, SABE Session "Gender Identity, Expectations, and Labor Market Outcomes" January 2021

Econometric Society Summer Schools in Dynamic Structural Econometrics

August~2021

2. Research Stay Grant

Economics Department, Yale University, USA

Spring 2020

cormac.odea@yale.edu

Supervision and reference Cormac O'Dea

3. Research Grants

Supplementary Project Grant CRC Rationality and Competition, "Attitudes, Expectations and the Mediating Role of Political Action"

Supplementary Project Grant CRC Rationality and Competition, "Gender and Higher Education Decision in France"

TEACHING

1. Introduction to Microeconomics, Undergraduate level, Yale University Spring, 2020 Instructor: Cprmac O'Dea

2. Structural Econometrics, Graduate level, BSE 2019 - 2021

3. Macroanatomy, Undergraduate Level, University Heidelberg 2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

Academic

Chair of Econometrics, Humboldt University Berlin, Germany

January 2016 - September 2016

Chair of Management, Humboldt University Berlin, Germany

 $April\ 2015\ -\ August\ 2015$

Collaborative Research Center "The Political Economy of Reforms"

April 2012 - July 2014

Mannheim, Germany

Private Sector

Deutsche Bahn AG, Berlin, Germany Internship Management Consulting

April - July 2017

KPMG AG, Berlin, Germany

Internship Forensic Data Analytics

October 2016 - March 2017

Stocard GmbH, Ludwigshafen, Germany

Working Student International Customer Management Internship Customer Analytics and Business Development November 2014 - July 2015

June - October 2014

SKILLS

Programming skills

Python, MatLab, R, Stata

Languages

Fluent: Bulgarian, English, German

Other: Spanish (advanced), French, Russian (basic)